THE BATTLE OF STALINGRAD

The Battle of Stalingrad was the decisive turning point of World War II. Although not originally a primary objective of Hitler's 1942 offensive, the city quickly became the focus of his entire campaign.

As the battle developed, both Hitler and Stalin became locked in a contest of wills, and Stalingrad, a place of horrors. Through broken streets and fire blackened buildings men fought room by room. In damp, rat infested basements the wounded lay, untended with the dying and the dead.

With winter came the last act in the drama, the Soviet counter-offensive, the destruction of the Romanian, Hungarian and Italian Armies and the encirclement of the mighty German 6th Army.

In recounting the sequence of events, the pivotal actions and key decisions, Battlefield draws on extensive resources including original, unpublished 
documents, combining this with rare archive material and full color 3D animation. A detailed analysis of the opposing forces and a clear description of each phase of the battle presents a unique and vivid account of the momentous events of these years.

ALSO AVAILABLE: "The Battle of Britain", "The Battle of Midway", "The Battle of Normandy"

Approximate Running time: 116 Minutes/B&W/Color/Not Rated/VHS  Photo Credits: FPG International (Map) Thomas Pike of Archival Research International. Program Copyright: 1994 La Mancha Productions - A Co-Production with PolyGram Video International Limited. All rights reserved. Manufactured and marketed by PolyGram Video, a division of PolyGram Records, Inc., New York, New York. All rights reserved. Unauthorized copying, reproduction, hiring, lending, public performance and broadcasting prohibited.
