THE BATTLE OF MIDWAY

In June 1942 the critical battle of the war in the Pacific was fought between American and Japanese carrier forces, separated by hundreds of miles of ocean. The Battle of Midway was a significant landmark in naval history and a turning point in the war at sea.

For the first time battleships fled before aircraft carriers, and major fleet engagements took place well beyond the range of visual contact. In the aftermath of the battle Japanese naval power was fatally damaged, and the ability to defend her new found maritime empire, seriously weakened.

Although heavily outnumbered, the American task force, through better intelligence appreciations, superior tactics and strategy, and remarkably good luck, achieved a stunning victory, destroying four Japanese carriers at the cost of only one of its own.

Drawing on extensive sources of original archive footage, including rare color material, and employing, the most modern techniques of animated 3D imaging, Battlefield assesses the opposing strategies and tactics, sets the battle within its historic context, and chronicles the sequence of events in a compelling narrative. Overall, the series presents one of the most comprehensive, analytical and vibrant accounts of World War II ever published.

ALSO AVAILABLE: "The Battle of Britain", "The Battle of Normandy", "The Battle of Stalingrad"

Approximate Running time: 116 Minutes/B&W/Color/Not Rated/VHS  Photo Credits: FPG International (Map) Thomas Pike of Archival Research International. Program Copyright: 1994 La Mancha Productions - A Co-Production with PolyGram Video International Limited. All rights reserved. Manufactured and marketed by PolyGram Video, a division of PolyGram Records, Inc., New York, New York. All rights reserved. Unauthorized copying, reproduction, hiring, lending, public performance and broadcasting prohibited.
