THE BATTLE OF NORMANDY

The Battle of Normandy was the last of the great set-piece engagements of World War II. It had been in planning for more than two years, and in preparation for almost as long.

In its execution, and particularly in its first critical phases, it was also one of the riskiest operations ever mounted. The French coast was known to be strongly defended, and behind the wire belts and fortifications of the Atlantic Wall were some of the most renowned and formidable divisions in the German order of battle.

For ten weeks, the Waffen SS and their supporting infantry and panzer formations fought a desperate battle against steadily mounting Allied forces. Their eventual defeat and destruction clearly signalled the beginning of the end for all but the most blindly loyal of Hitler's soldiers.

Battlefield offers a unique perspective of the key battles of World War II, combining extensive use of archive footage with full color 3D animation and a compelling and vivid narrative. Detailed portraits of the principal commanders and leaders, and profiles of the main weapon systems complete a fascinating analysis of the forces in conflict. Battlefield is a series that chronicles the decisive events and critical battles that shaped history.

ALSO AVAILABLE: "The Battle of Britain", "The Battle of Midway", "The Battle of Stalingrad"

Approximate Running time: 116 Minutes/B&W/Color/Not Rated/VHS  Photo Credits: FPG International (Map) Thomas Pike of Archival Research International. Program Copyright: 1994 La Mancha Productions - A Co-Production with PolyGram Video International Limited. All rights reserved. Manufactured and marketed by PolyGram Video, a division of PolyGram Records, Inc., New York, New York. All rights reserved. Unauthorized copying, reproduction, hiring, lending, public performance and broadcasting prohibited.
