THE BATTLE OF BRITAIN

The Battle of Britain wrote a new chapter in the history of warfare. It was the first time that air forces alone determined the outcome of a military campaign. At stake was the ultimate prize, the future freedom of the British Isles and the continuation of the war to victory.

For a battle of such importance, the actual fighting was done by remarkably small numbers of men, and the courage and skill of individuals mattered in a way almost unique in the annals of warfare. Yet the battle was also a contest between nations, in which millions played a role. Beneath the vapor trails that charted the ebb and flow of battle, industry labored to turn out the aircraft that were the means to victory. Radar and communications systems were honed to a new level of sophistication and, in the bomb damaged streets, armies of volunteers fought the fires, cleared away the rubble and manned the air defenses.

Battlefield offers a unique perspective of the key battles of World War II, combining extensive use of archive footage with full color 3D animation and a compelling and vivid narrative. Detailed portraits of the principal commanders and leaders, and profiles of the main weapon systems complete a fascinating analysis of the forces in conflict. Battlefield is a series that chronicles the decisive events and critical battles that shaped history.

ALSO AVAILABLE: "The Battle of Normandy", "The Battle of Midway", "The Battle of Stalingrad"

Approximate Running time: 116 Minutes/B&W/Color/Not Rated/VHS  Photo Credits: FPG International (Map) Thomas Pike of Archival Research International. Program Copyright: 1994 La Mancha Productions - A Co-Production with PolyGram Video International Limited. All rights reserved. Manufactured and marketed by PolyGram Video, a division of PolyGram Records, Inc., New York, New York. All rights reserved. Unauthorized copying, reproduction, hiring, lending, public performance and broadcasting prohibited.
